

KASHISH MITTAL

Dot.Net Developer

Phone: +91.9034391574

Email: kashishmittal1750@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/kashish-mittal-4265a8185

PROFILE

Participated in requirement gathering sessions with the client and preparation/modifying of the requirements in Requirement Specification document using Xml and Json.

Implemented OO Design and Concepts data modeling to analyze and define data requirements need to support business requirements.

Designed User Interface using Web Forms, Win forms, ASP.NET, Server Controls and Visual Studio.Net.

Created user interfaces using ASP.NET Web forms and Web Server controls

Studied Business Requirements, Analysis and converted business requirements into technical specifications.

Coded the Business Logic layer and Data Access layer using C#.NET.

Worked on ASP.NET State management, using Sessions and ASP.Net Caching features using Output Cache.

Extensively used ADO.NET classes provided by the .NET Framework 5.0 for database connectivity.

Developed data access assemblies in C# to connect to SQL Server database and isolated data access logic from business layer and front end by defining several strongly typed dataset.

Written SQL Queries, Stored Procedures, functions using SQL Server.

Highly flexible in Testing Using Postman

EDUCATION

. Bachelor of Engineering / Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering

Sharda University

UGC

Greater Noida, Uttar Pradesh

Graduated, May 2021

Marks 75 %

Intermediate, Class 12th, Non Medical

Pratap Public School

CBSE

Karnal, Haryana

Completed, March 2017

Marks 70 %

· High School, Class 10th

Pratap Public School

CBSE

Karnal, Haryana

Completed, March 2015

Marks 7.4 [CGPA]

WORK EXPERIENCE

July 2021 - December 2021

Software Engineer

Affixious Consulting Pvt. Ltd.

Noida, Uttar Pradesh

- · Doing all tasks with are guided by our Supervisors.
- Familiarity with the ASP.NET framework, SQL Server and design/architectural patterns (e.g. Model-View-Controller (MVC)
- Understanding with architecture styles/APIs (REST, RPC).
- Understanding of Agile methodologies
- Very well known how to manage the code and do all debugging on live Web Api.

INTERNSHIP

August 2020 - October 2020

Digital Marketing Intern

Pochocki Technical Training and Services

Noida, Uttar Pradesh

Fullfill tasks set out bu supervisors from several departments.

Attend meeting and take minutes.

Perform research at a supervisors request.

Update social media platforms and write copy to posts.

Create images for social media posts.

TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Deep Learning IIT Ropar, NPTEL, 2021
- Artificial Intelligence, Microsoft, 2021
- · Getting Stated with Node Js , Simplelearn, 2021
- Full Stack JAVA Developer, Udemy, 2020
- Database Management With Sql, Oracle, 2020
- · Internet Of Things, Sharda University, 2020

COMPUTER PROFICIENCY

Operating Systems

Windows 7/8/10

Software

- Microsoft Visual Studio 2019
- VS Code

ENGINEERING SKILLS

Languages

- · Asp. Net C#
- Java
- JavaScript

Web Servers

- · Apache Tomcat Server
- Xampp Server

Web Components

- Jquery
- Rest
- · NewtonSoft.Json

Networks

· Computer Networks

Database

- SQL Server
- MySQL

Development Tools

- Eclipse IDE
- NetBeans Ide
- Microsoft Visual Studio 2019

LANGUAGES

- · Hindi ••••
- English

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

Design, development, implementation and maintenance of Web Applications using Asp.Net, Web Services, WCF Services, C#.NET,
 ADO.NET, SQL Server, C#, and .Net

Framework

INTERESTS

- · Love to play basketball as well as chess
- · Listening all kinds of music
- Travelling
- · Main Focus on Improving my Career Skills

PROJECT

Project 1 AIRLINE RESERVATION SYSTEM

Period: August 2019 - December 2019
Technologies: By Using JAVA, MySQL, & CSS

In this **JAVA Major project** mainly we are going to concentrate on ticket booking function, this function will take the user inputs like their requirements (flight name, flight source & destination, Number of seats, Seat numbers), after entering all of his/her requirements in this application, it can check at backend & provide us the total information about flights. When we open the first page of this project we can find the basic information (basic fair & discounts) about today flight timings.

Project 2 Online Shopping System
Period: July 2020 - December 2020

Technologies: Java, JSP, & CSS

The Online Shopping System has become an essential tool for sellers and also for buyers. The online shopping system in java allows buyers to buy goods/products directly from the seller website and it saves time and money of buyer. There is an advantage of the sellers to attract more customers using online shopping systems and it promotes cashless transactions.

Project 3 Employee Management System
Period: September 2021 - October 2021

Technologies: Asp .NET , C#, SQL Server

Employee Management System C# is made with C# programming language and ASPX Designer using Visual Studio 2019, employee management system helps to add, edit, record, and delete any employee details of an organization. Users can register and login to view all entries of the employees. The software features functionalities such as login and registration, add, edit or delete employee records and also view their entries.

PERSONAL

Father's Name: Mr. Sanjeev Mittal Marital Status: Single Birthday: 31/10/1998 Nationality: Indian

Gender: Male

Address: Kashish Mittal

H.no.: 1750, Sector -7, U.E., Karnal, Haryana

Karnal, Haryana132001

India

Declaration

I, Kashish Mittal, hereby declare that the information contained herein is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.